Preliminary Inventory of the Fred Charles Iklé papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Fred Charles Iklé papers
1972-1988
96025
Hoover Institution Archives
26 manuscript boxes (10.8 linear feet)
Speeches and writings, correspondence, memoranda, reports, testimony, schedules, appointment books, telephone logs, and printed matter relating to the Strategic Arms Limitation Talks and other arms control issues, the 1980 presidential campaign of Ronald Reagan, and American defense policy during the presidential administrations of Richard M. Nixon, Gerald R. Ford, and Ronald Reagan. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Iklé, Fred Charles.
Access
Collection is open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1996.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Biographical Note
Director, United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, 1973-1977; Under Secretary of Defense for policy, 1981-1988.
Scope and Content of Collection
Speeches and writings, correspondence, memoranda, reports, testimony, schedules, appointment books, telephone logs, and printed matter relating to the Strategic Arms Limitation Talks and other arms control issues, the 1980 presidential campaign of Ronald Reagan, and American defense policy during the presidential administrations of Richard M. Nixon, Gerald R. Ford, and Ronald Reagan.
Arms control.; Nuclear weapons.; United States--Defenses.; United States--Military policy.; United States--Politics and government--1969-1974.; United States--Politics and government--1974-1977.; United States--Politics and government--1981-1989.; United States. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency.; United States. Department of Defense.; Presidents--United States--Election--1980.; Reagan, Ronald.
- DIRECTOR, UNITED STATES ARMS CONTROL AND DISARMAMENT AGENCY (1973-1977) FILE, 1973-1979 (Boxes 1-9)
  - Nomination as Director hearing, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Appointment calendars, 1973-1976
  - Appointment books
    - 1973-1975
    - 1976 (Box 2)
  - Telephone call books, 1973-1976
  - Administrative files, 1973-1977
  - Invitations, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Personnel possibilities file, 1973
  - Correspondence, 1973-1976
    - Congress
    - Council on Foreign Relations
    - General
      - A-P
      - Q-Z (Box 4)
  - Speech files, 1973-1977
  - Special memoranda and letters, 1973-1976
    - General
    - Strategic Arms Limitation Talks
  - Subject file
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes some post-1977 material.
    - Arms Control Act (Box 5)
    - Chemical and environmental warfare
    - Mutual and Balanced Force Reduction negotiations
    - Nuclear non-proliferation
      - 1974-1976
      - 1976 (Box 6)
    - Ozone effect
    - Strategic Arms Limitation Talks I
    - Strategic Arms Limitation Talks II (Box 7)
    - Strategic Arms Limitation Talks debate
      - 1976-1977 (Box 8)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 9)
    - Technology transfer
- POLITICAL FILE, 1977-1988 (Boxes 10-15)
  - Hoover Institution foreign policy contribution, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Republican National Committee publications
  - Republican National Committee Advisory Council files, 1979-1980
  - Appointment book, 1980
  - 1980 presidential campaign files
    - Ronald Reagan speeches, statements and press coverage
    - Reagan Advisory Group files (Box 11)
    - Correspondence
    - Press contacts
    - Republican Party platform
    - General background files
    - General background files (Box 12)
    - Subject file
      Includes material from 1980-1981 presidential transition team.
      - Africa
      - Aid and human rights
      - America's message abroad (broadcasting) (Box 13)
      - Americas
      - Asia
      - Defense
      - Iran (Box 14)
      - Middle East
      - North Atlantic Treaty Organization
      - Soviet Union
  - 1980-1981 presidential transition team file (Box 15)
  - 1984 presidential campaign file
  - 1988 presidential campaign file
- UNDER SECRETARY, UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE (1981-1988) FILE
  - Confirmation as Under Secretary file, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Organizational manuals and directories of office of Under Secretary
  - Appointment books
    - 1981-1982
    - 1983-1984 (Box 17)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 18)
    - 1986-1988 (Box 19)
  - Appointment notes
    - 1981-1982 (Box 20)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 21)
    - 1985-1988 (Box 22)
  - Telephone logs
    - 1981-1983 (Box 23)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 24)
  - Telephone call lists
    - 1983-1984
    - 1985-1988 (Box 25)
  - Social schedule files
    - 1981
    - 1983-1988 (Box 26)
  - Long range schedule files, 1986-1988
  - Subject file
    - Grenada
    - Police training
    - Radio Marti
- DECLASSIFIED U.S. GOVERNMENT RECORDS, 1982-1988 (Reading room workstation)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Available as PDF files. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover, thereunder by date of creation.
  - 2010 release of records, 1983-1987
    - Map of India, undated
    - Weekly schedules, 1983-1984
    - Daily telephone logs, 1986-1987
  - 2017 release of records, 1982-1988
    - Weekly schedules, 1983-1985
    - Materials re dinner party for Dr. V. S. Arunachalam of India on August 12, 1985, circa 1985
    - Daily telephone logs, 1986-1988